LAWS OF REPUBLIC OF TURKEY
土耳其共和国法律
Poor Agah.
可怜的Agah
Munir?
Where are you, my boy?
你在哪里？
Munir?
Come on boy, it's time for breakfast.
快出来，该吃早餐了
Where are you?
你在哪里？
Munir!
Munir?
Where are you, sir?
你在哪？
Munir?
Have you gone to a vacation or something?
你去度假了吗？
No.
没有
So Munir has never been alone?
Munir从来没有一个人在家待过吗？
No.
没有
You haven't delayed his treatment?
你从来没有延误它的治疗？
No, I was giving him the cat food that you gave me for his...
没有，我给它的食物是您给我用于治疗它的......
Acute kidney failure.
急性肾功能衰竭
Yes.
是
Did he die because of that?
他是因此而死吗？
Because of acute kidney failure.
因为急性肾衰竭
Not just that. The cat has also been dehydrated.
不仅如此，它也已经脱水了
How?
什么？
MUNIR - MY LOVELY CAT
MUNIR - 我可爱的猫
Man, what are we going to do with her?
兄弟，我们该拿她怎么办？
She's been here for six months.
她来这里已经六个月了
and they are still talking about Nevra.
但人们仍然在谈论Nevra
You are bothered because you couldn't sleep with her.
你是因为睡不到她才觉得难受吧
Fuck off. What the fuck are you talking about?
滚蛋，你他妈在说什么？
How many of my classmates is crazy about coming here
我有很多同学想来这里都想疯了
do you know?
你知道吗？
She literally came here out of nowhere.
她简直就是凭空出现的
Do you know why? Because she is a woman.
你知道为什么吗？因为她是女人
They called it positive discrimination.
他们称其为积极性区别对待
What part of this is positive?
哪里有积极的一面？
There are many strong men out there.
外面有好多猛男呢
But for them it's necessary to put Nevra into the spotlight.
但对他们来说，有必要将Nevra放在首位
Nevra, Nevra.
Fuck that thing called 'human resources'.
去他妈的“人力资源部”
What does it have to do with that?
这和这有什么关系？
Let's say you're out there with Nevra.
假设您和Nevra在一起
Would you trust Nevra? Could you trust her?
你会信任Nevra吗？你会信任她吗？
I would trust more if it was a man holding the gun.
如果是个拿枪的男人，我会相信的
At least it would be clear what he'd do.
至少很清楚他会做什么
See
是啊
She can get the fuck out of here.
她应该滚出这个地方了
But she shouldn't go without a fuck.
但是绝不能让她轻易离开
Definitely.
必须的
Nurten, could you schedule an appointment for next week, please?
Nurten，你能安排下星期的预约吗？
Agah Beyoglu.
Thanks.
谢谢
Now...
好了
First thing we should do is to inform your family.
首先我们应该通知您的家人
They have to know about this first.
他们必须先知道这件事
Your wife had passed away.
你老婆去世了
Yes.
是
It's been 10 years.
已经十年了
You have a daughter.
你有一个女儿
Yes, but she's not here, she's living abroad.
是的，但是她不在这里，她住在国外
Doesn't matter, you should inform her.
没关系，你应该通知她
She may even call me, I would like to talk to her.
她甚至可以打电话给我，我想和她聊一下
Are we clear?
清楚吗？
Yes.
是
Bon appetit.
祝你好胃口
I was thinking if we should redo the test, in case the results are wrong.
我在想是否应该重做检测，以防结果不准确
I knew a guy named Necmi.
我认识一个叫Necmi的人
- They said he had cancer but then... - I know.
-他们说他得了癌症，但是后来......-我知道
I know.
我知道
It's hard to accept.
很难接受
But the results are clear.
但是结果很清楚
So are the symptoms.
症状也是如此
For me, there is no doubt in this diagnosis, Agah.
诊断毫无疑问，Agah
You have early stage Alzheimer's.
你有早期的老年痴呆症
Yes, Dad?
爸爸
Honey.
宝贝
Dad, I can't do it. I can't bear this anymore.
爸爸，我做不下去，我再也受不了了。
What happened? I'll call the Chief Inspector
怎么了？我打电话给总检察长
Dad, I'm not a kid. I don't want you to call anyone.
爸爸，我不是孩子了，我不需要你打电话给任何人
Then why did you call me?
那你为什么给我打电话
Daughter?
闺女？
Dau...
闺......
But doctor, I remember everything.
但是医生，我记得所有事情
People forget things when they have Alzheimer's.
人们患老年痴呆症时会忘记事情
I worked at the courthouse for 27 years.
我在法院工作了27年
If I went there now I'd remember where every file is.
如果我现在过去，我记得所有文件的位置
You are in the early stages.
你还处于初期
Ask me then, anything. My anniversary, friends' phone numbers...
随便问我生日，朋友的电话号码等等……
I know them by heart.
这些我都记得很熟
My friends used to call me I was like a phone book.
我的朋友曾经说我就像电话簿
Back then we couldn't save the numbers so I memorized them.
当年我们无法保存电话号码，所以我就记在脑子里
Agah.
Agah
You forgot to give water to your cat.
你忘记给猫喝水了
You forgot to feed him.
你忘了给它喂食
He starved to death.
它饿死了
How could I do that? How?
我怎么会这样？怎么回事？
Poor Munir.
可怜的Munir
Look, this is an early diagnosis.
听好，这是早期诊断
This will be of tremendous help for the treatment.
对治疗有极大的帮助
We have patients that lived 20 years after the diagnosis.
我们有一些患者在确诊后已经生活了20年
So rest assured.
所以请放心
Lived 20 years but do they remember what they lived?
活了20年，但他们还记得自己的生活吗？
Alzheimer's directly affects memory.
老年痴呆症直接影响记忆
It's one of the main reasons for dementia.
这是痴呆症的主要原因之一
But we will do all we can to stall this and to keep your mind alive.
但是，我们将竭尽所能保持您的头脑活跃
But sooner or later, I will forget things, right?
但是迟早我会忘记的，对吗？
Don't think about this now.
现在先不要考虑这些
All my memories, experiences will be erased, they will go away.
我所有的记忆，经历将被抹去，并且消失
What will happen to me?
然后我会怎样？
I mean...
我是说……
Phone numbers aren't that important.
电话号码没有多重要
But what will happen to my personality?
但是我的人格将会怎样？
Wouldn't it be erased too?
也会被抹掉吗？
I will forget what kind of man I am.
我会忘记我是什么样的人
You are alive but you don't exist.
你还活着，但你并不存在
How can someone endure this?
怎么会有人忍受得了呢？
You may put this in your pocket.
您可以把它放在口袋里
I'll check the sound, say something, please.
我来检查一下声音，请说点什么。
What should I say? Hi.
我应该说什么？
You can count the days of the week.
您可以数一数每周有多少天
Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
星期五，星期六，星期天
Monday.
星期一
Tuesday, Wednesday.
星期二，星期三
Thursday, Friday.
星期四，星期五
That should do.
可以了
Let's get started.
让我们开始吧
I'll start with a basic question.
我从一个基本问题开始
How does it feel to be the only woman
作为唯一的女人感觉如何
working in an homicide bureau with 140 staff members?
在拥有140名员工的凶杀科工作？
How does it feel?
感觉怎么样？
Of course it's amazing.
当然很棒
I feel very privileged.
我感到非常荣幸
First of all, all of us here are part of the homicide bureau.
首先，我们所有人都是凶杀科的成员
It's impossible to see anything like gender discrimination
这里几乎没有任何性别歧视
or any other sexist approaches in this institution.
或的其他任何性别歧视的方式
Instead of any problems, my friends are supporting me so much.
没有任何问题，我的朋友们都很支持我
Which also means another responsibility for me.
对我来说也是一种责任
I am trying to do my best to be worthy of their support.
我正在尽我所能来得到他们的支持
You studied public administration, right?
您学习过公共管理，对吗？
Yes.
是
You even worked as a manager in private sector
您甚至在私营企业做过经理
but then you decided to enroll at the police academy.
但后来您决定报名参加警察学院
Yes.
是
Why did you decide to become a police officer?
您为什么决定当警察？
I always thought about it because...
我一直都想做，因为……
The greatest man I know was a policeman... My father.
我的父亲是一名警察，他是我认识的最伟大的人
Who is currently retired.
现在退休了
You start to understand things as you grow.
随着成长，我开始理解一些事情
We barely saw our father.
我们几乎看不到我们父亲
Maybe at the weekends, just for a day.
也许周末可以，但只有一天
I used to resent him.
我曾经很讨厌他
I used to tell him that he cares about other people more.
我曾经说他更关心别人
It seems that my father's job is to care about other people.
看来我父亲的工作就是关心别人
And he ingrained this concept in me so much
他把这个概念深深地印在我的脑海里
that I don't know how to live any other way.
以至于我不知道如何以其他方式生活
I actually repeat this in every interview
我在每次访谈时都会重复这句话
but being a police officer is not a job for me, never has been.
但是当警察对我来说从来就不是一份工作
There is a concept called goodness.
有一个概念叫做善良
For me, being a police officer means being a part of that goodness.
对我来说，成为一名警察意味着成为善良的一部分
That's my purpose...
那就是我的目标
To become a good person...
成为一个好人
Deva!
Deva, answer me! Where were you last night?
Deva，回答我！昨晚你在哪里？
Deva, answer me!
Deva，回答我！
Yes?
喂？
Zuhal, hello my dear.
Zuhal，你好亲爱的
Wait a minute.
等一下
Tell me where were you last night.
告诉我昨晚你在哪里
Look at me!
看着我！
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Come with me then.
那你跟我来啊
You're not going!
你不可以去！
Deva, I'll fuck you up!
Deva，我要揍死你!
Deva!
Yes?
喂？
My dear, is this a bad time? Did I wake you up? What time is it there?
亲爱的，这个时间不方便吗？我吵醒你了吗？现在几点了？
No, we are awake. It's morning here. Is something wrong?
不，我们都醒着，这边是早上，出什么事情了？
Do I need a reason to call my daughter?
我给我的女儿打电话还需要理由吗？
I don't remember the last time you called.
我都不记得你上一次来电话了
I'm the one who always calls.
一直都是我给你打电话
How is Deva?
Deva怎么样？
Deva is making me crazy!
Deva快把我逼疯了
Deva doesn't listen to me, we can't even talk...
Deva不听我的话，我们甚至不能沟通……
Dad, did you take the vitamins I sent you?
爸爸，你吃了我寄给你的维生素吗？
I did, thank you.
吃了，谢谢
But don't take them in high doses, they may cause diabetes.
但是不可以吃太多，可能会导致糖尿病
You take one.
记一下
And keep taking for three months...
持续服用三个月
Take them for three months then stop taking for a month.
服用三个月，然后停用一个月
Then you take them for another three months. Don't ignore it.
然后你再服用三个月，别忘了
You didn't listen either.
你也不听话
What?
什么？
You didn't listen to us when you were young either.
你小时候也不听我们的
Is that so?
是吗？
How would you know?
你怎么知道的？
How would you know? Deva is 16 years old.
你怎么知道的？Deva今年16岁
When I was 16, it was my fifth year on boarding school.
我16岁那年是我在寄宿学校的第5年
Remember that you sent me away?
还记得你把我送走了吗？
Were you with me?
你和我在一起吗？
Was my mother there?
妈妈和我在一起吗？
How would you know if I had listened someone or not?
你怎么知道我听话不听话？
Did you know what I was doing?
你知道我在做什么吗？
Do you know what I'm doing right now? No!
你知道我现在在做什么吗？
What can I do, my dear. You ran away to the other side of the world, to Australia.
我能怎么办，亲爱的，你逃到了世界的另一端，去了澳大利亚
Dad, I'm getting a divorce.
爸，我要离婚了
Do you have any idea about this?
你有什么想说的吗？
Dad, I'm sorry.
爸，对不起
I didn't mean to. I am very upset.
我不是故意的，我很难过
I'm sorry, please forgive me.
对不起，请原谅我
Were you going to say something? Were you...
你刚才要说什么？刚才……
I propose a toast for Nevra.
我提议为Nevra干杯
Different interviews, every week.
每周都有不同的采访
Finally, one of us is famous.
我们之中总算出了个名人
Don't be silly, I'm not famous.
别傻了，我可不是什么名人
Oh, wait, what was it?
等等，这是什么？
To Nevra...
敬Nevra……
Who reassures friends and awes foes.
让朋友安心，让敌人敬畏
To Nevra the po-po!
敬Nevra宝宝！
- What do you mean by po-po? - She said po-po.
-你说啥？-她说宝宝
They say that in the movies all the time. I've always wanted to say po-po.
总是在电影里看到，我一直想说
Nice, are you finished? May I drink now?
很好，你们说完了吗，我可以现在喝吗？
All jokes aside, Nevra, why did you become a police officer?
撇开玩笑不提，Nevra，你为什么去当警察？
What do you mean 'why'?
你是什​​么意思？
It's a simple question.
这是一个简单的问题
Why did you become a fascist?
你为什么成为法西斯主义者？
What are you saying? Are you a troll?
你在说什么？中二了吗？
Are you drunk?
你醉了吗？
Hang on, I am curious.
等一下，我很好奇
We meet very rarely and you say these things.
我们很少聚在一起，你别这样说话
You are actually asking me this...
你其实是在问我
Why didn't I get into an insurance company?
为什么我没有进入保险公司？
Why I am not in the ministry of finance?
为什么我没有去财政部？
Why I am not a banker?
为什么我没有做银行家？
Why I didn't act like a revolutionist in college and then marry a rich guy
为什么我不像大学里的革命主义者那样，然后嫁给有钱人
and sit on my ass all day without working, like you?
像你一样没事做混日子？
Here is my answer...
这是我的答案
I didn't want to.
我不想这样
I wanted to do...
我想做
I wanted to do something...
我想做点事
Something real.
真实的东西
What is that?
做什么？
It's a simple question.
这是一个简单的问题
Why did you become a fascist?
你为什么成为法西斯主义者？
I'm just kidding.
我只是在开玩笑
She's offended.
她生气了
She was like that in college too.
她上学时也是这样
Come on.
来吧
To reuniting after all these years.
敬这么多年后的重聚。
To this beautiful night.
敬这个美丽的夜晚
Mumtaz!
Agah, I'm here...
Agah，我在这里
- Come, Agah. Come here. - Excuse me.
-这边，Agah-借过
That's why I don't come here.
那就是为什么我不来这里
The crowd, the drunks, the noise...
人群，醉汉，喧闹声……
Bums in my apartment are enough for me
我公寓里的流浪汉就够多了
and you brought me here.
你还带我来这里
You are used to this Agah.
你已经习惯了
I'm not. I couldn't get used to them.
没有，我还是不习惯
How long have you lived here?
您在这里住了多久了？
If you don't want to live here, sell your apartments
如果您不想住在这里，就卖掉您的公寓
and move away.
离开这里
I won't go!
我才不走！
My last name is Beyoglu, they'll go.
我是姓Beyoglu的，要走也是他们走
- You will. - I won't.
-你会的-我不
- You will brother! - I won't go away.
-你会走的！-我才不走
I won't.
绝不
It's been so long since I saw you, Agah.
很久没见到你了，阿加
If I hadn't called you, we were never going to meet.
如果我没有给你打电话，我们可能永远都不会见面
What's wrong man? Is there someone in your life?
怎么了，你的生活中是否有你爱的人？
Are you dating someone? Are you ignoring us?
你在和谁约会吗？还是在忽略我们？
I'm not ignoring, I just don't have time.
我没有忽略，我只是没有时间
Fuck off. In our age, time is all we have.
滚蛋，我们都这把年纪了，有的是时间
You are a joke.
你真是可笑
Don't become introverted.
别这么内向
I can come and take you to Bosphorus in mornings.
我早上可以带你去博斯普鲁斯海峡
Come here.
过来
- Yes, sir. - Taste this.
-是的，先生 -尝尝这个
- Does it taste bad? - Just taste it.
-味道不好吗 -尝一尝
I can tell the cook to prepare another for you.
我可以告诉厨师为您准备另一个
Why?
为什么？
You didn't like it.
你不喜欢
I didn't say that. I said 'taste this'.
我没要你另外准备，我是说让你尝一尝
Why are you bothering him?
你为什么要打扰他？
He's offering a new one.
他另外准备新的给你
That's not the point. People don't listen to each other.
那不是重点，人们不互相倾听
Maybe it tastes good and I don't get it.
也许味道不错，我不明白
Just go back to work. Come on.
回去上班吧，去吧
- Go. - No!
-走吧 -不用
You surprised me.
你真让我吃惊
Our peaceful, sweet Agah
我们平静，温柔的Agah
scolding the waiter. I can't believe it.
骂了服务员，我真不敢相信
That's not the point.
那不是重点
People don't listen to each other properly.
人们不能很好地互相倾听
Automatic answers without waiting.
自动应答，无需等待
Everything is automated now, and they say we can't get along.
现在一切都自动化了，他们竟然说我们无法相处
Don't get mad, okay.
别生气了
Let's eat and go, we'll go somewhere else.
我们吃完就走吧，我们去别的地方
I shouldn't come, it's late.
我不该来，太晚了
That's the automatic answer. It's not late, it's 8:30 pm.
那是自动答案，一点都不晚，现在是晚上8:30
Muazzez also asked to see you.
Muazzez还想见你呢
She told me to bring you with me.
她叫我带你过去
Our friends organized an event that we should...
我们的朋友组织了一个活动，我们应该
Where did that event come out from?
那件事是从哪里来的？
For god's sake! We're going.
看在上帝的份上！我们要去
That's it. My prostate destroyed me.
就是这样，我的前列腺毁了我
Destroyed me, made me miserable.
毁了我，使我痛苦
What am I doing here?
带我来这里干嘛？
Just hang on, I'll introduce you to someone.
等等，我给你介绍一个人
So is that why you brought me here?
这就是你把我带到这里的原因？
Did you set a trap for me?
这是个什么陷阱吗？
That's Nukhet. And this is my friend I told you about, Agah.
那是Nukhet，这是我曾跟你提过的朋友，Agah
Nukhet.
Nukhet
Hi, nice to meet you.
你好，很高兴见到你
Hello.
你好
Nukhet has been taking tango lessons
Nukhet一直在上探戈课
and I told her that there is a tango master here.
我告诉她你是一位探戈大师
Come on...
得了吧
You wouldn't mind teaching Nukhet a thing or two, right?
您不会介意指点Nukhet跳舞吧？
It would be my pleasure.
这是我的荣幸
So... They're doing a great job, aren't they?
所以他们做得很好，不是吗？
Yeah but, what's with us?
是的，但是跟我们有什么关系吗？
You are confused again, why don't you drink something?
你又一头雾水，为什么不去喝点什么呢？
No, I don't want to. I don't want to be like them.
不，我不想像他们一样
They will be drunk soon.
他们很快就会喝醉了
They will embarrass themselves.
他们会让自己难堪
And they will regret everything when they wake up.
当他们醒来时会后悔的
Why would they regret?
他们为什么会后悔？
They'll just get drunk.
他们喝醉了
They won't remember anything in the morning.
不会记住任何事情
How nice.
多好
Since I won't remember
既然我不记得了
I can do anything I want, is that so?
我可以做任何我想做的事，是吗？
Exactly.
正是
How nice.
多好
I won't remember, so I can do anything.
我不记得了，所以我可以做任何事情
Won't they wake up in the morning?
他们不会在早上醒来吗？
You're obsessed with this again, Agah.
你又在纠结这个了，Agah
Mumtaz!
Mumtaz
Eat one's heart out...
伤心欲绝
Interesting sentence.
有趣的句子
That's conscience.
那是良心
It can eat your heart out, literally.
从字面上看，它可以吞噬您的心
Forgetting forever.
永远忘记
Forgetting that you are forgetting.
忘记你正在忘记
Yes, that's it.
对，就是那样
I will forget everything.
我会忘记一切
I won't remember anything.
我什么都不记得了
To Agah.
致Agah
I'm not forgetting.
我不会忘记
One more please.
再来一杯
Agah!
Are you leaving?
你要走了吗？
I had an emergency.
我有点急事
You can call me whenever you want.
你随时可以打电话给我
I am very glad to meet you.
很高兴认识你
So am I.
我也是
Have a good night.
祝你有一个美好的夜晚
ARDICHAN COURTHOUSE PROPERTY AND EVIDENCE UNIT
ARDICHAN法院物证部门
There was no rape.
没有强奸
I accept the murder but there was no rape.
我接受谋杀，但没有强奸
INTERROGATION CAMERA
审讯相机
She is not the only fish in the sea.
她不是海中唯一的鱼
- All the girls love me. - Is that so?
-女孩们都喜欢我 -是吗？
- They melt with my one look. - Really?
-他们融化于我的一个眼神 -真的吗？
For example, that woman.
例如那个女人
Which woman?
哪个女人
That police woman.
那个女警察
- She was running after me... - Is that so?
-她在追我-是吗？
Told me to stop.
告诉我停下来
She pulled her gun and I stopped.
她拔枪我停了下来
Then I turned and looked at her.
然后我转身看着她
- Do you know what happened? - What?
-你知道发生了什么吗？-什么？
- She looked like she literally melted. - Really?
-她看起来好像真的融化了-真的吗？
So, guys...
伙计们
TOLGA YAZGAN CHIEF INSPECTOR
TOLGA YAZGAN首席检验员
This incident stays in this room.
这件事到此为止
- Is that clear? - It is clear, Chief.
-清楚吗？-清楚，长官
Firuz?
What?
什么？
Yeah, it is Chief.
是的，长官
Guys...
伙计们
Do you think I don't know about your messing with Nevra?
你们以为我不知道你们招惹Nevra的事吗？
No one will mess with Nevra from now on!
从现在起，不准任何人惹Nevra
Is that clear?
明白了吗？
And you will be working on documentation in administration.
你将调到行政部门做文书工作
No more field duties.
不再执行外勤任务
Guys, we are done. Why are you still here?
还愣着干什么？
Go.
走
CERTIFICATE
证书
"Not Responsible" by Tom Jones.
汤姆·琼斯（Tom Jones）的“不负责任”
CRIMINAL RECORDS
犯罪记录
Your daughter hasn't called yet.
你女儿还没打电话给我
She's very busy, but I told her.
她很忙，但我已经告诉她了
What did she say?
她说了什么？
- She'll come here soon. - Nice.
-她很快就会来的-不错
Are you taking your medicines?
吃药了吗？
- Yes. - Nice.
- 是好
Okay.
好的
Recently...
最近
Last week...
上个星期
Have you gotten angry for no reason?
你无缘无故生气了吗？
Something like a tantrum.
发脾气之类的
- Not really. - Nice.
-没有-不错
I'm asking this because this tantrum may occur any time.
我问这个是因为您随时都可能发脾气
You may feel insecure.
您可能会感到不安全
You may be sensitive about something that you haven't cared about before.
您可能对以前没有在意过的事情很敏感
These things may happen.
这些事情都有可能发生
If something like this happens, take a note.
如果发生了类似的情况，记下来
Have you started doing your homework?
您开始做功课了吗？
Have you started taking notes?
您开始记笔记了吗？
MY NAMES IS AGAH BEYOGLU. I THREW MY TV INTO THE STREET.
我的名字叫AGAH BEYOGLUI，我把我的电视机扔到街上
- I'm taking notes, yes. - Very good.
-我有做笔记-非常好
Okay, what about physical activities?
好，体育锻炼呢？
You were going to walk.
你要多走路
You should make an effort, I said simple sports may also do.
你应该努力，做简单的运动也可以
Yes, I am doing those things.
是的，我在做这些事
- I'm very active nowadays. - Very good.
-我现在很活跃-非常好
Okay, let's talk about mental activities.
好吧，让我们谈谈心理活动
We should activate your brain neurons that have never worked until now.
我们应该激活那些从未起作用的大脑神经元
How will we do that?
要怎么做？
For example...
例如
One of my patients was familiar with Latin languages.
我的一位患者熟悉拉丁语言
And she started learning Japanese.
她开始学习日语
And she benefited a lot from it.
她从中受益匪浅
You want me to learn Japanese?
你要我学日语吗？
No.
没有
Everyone has a different interest.
每个人都有不同的兴趣
There must be something that you always wanted to do but you couldn't.
一定有您一直想做但做不到的事情
There are many things I want to do.
有很多我想做的事
That's it, very good.
就是这样，很好
Look, whatever it is, however it is done...
不管是什么事，要如何做
You will start doing it with utmost planning.
开始做计划吧
Look, planning is the key word here.
计划是这里的关键词
You should have daily, weekly, monthly plans.
您应该有每日，每周，每月的计划
You should check if you are following those plans accordingly.
并且应该检查是否按照计划执行
You won't cut corners.
不要走任何捷径
You'll make it complicated.
让这件事变得复杂
You'll detail it.
做好细节
Let's assume that you'll water a plant.
假设您要给植物浇水
You'll spray every leaf of that plant
要把植物的每一片叶子都喷水
one by one, patiently.
一片接一片，耐心地做
You should enjoy what you're doing.
你会很享受你正在做的事情
Agah, you'll do that in such an impeccable way
Agah，这样你会做到完美
that the plant won't be able to tell if it's raining or you're watering it.
这颗植物根本无法判断是在下雨还是在浇水
Are we clear?
明白吗？
- We are clear. - Nice.
-我很清楚 -很好
Very nice.
非常好
Okay, now tell me...
好，跟我说说
How have you been feeling lately?
您最近感觉如何？
I've never felt so good.
从来没有这么好过
SECURITY CLEARANCE
安全检查
IDENTIFICATION CARD COPY
身份证副本
Damn it.
谁啊？
- What? - You are a mechanic, so you should know.
-什么事？-你是机械师，所以你应该知道
Why are mechanics always late?
为什么机械师总是迟到？
What?
什么？
Our elevator mechanic for instance, we waited for so long but he didn't come.
例如我们的电梯技工，我们等了很久，但他没来
Then he came, but he was late.
然后他来了，但是他来晚了
Who are you, what are you saying?
你是谁，你在说什么？
Are we going to wait for mechanics our whole lives?
我们要一辈子等机械师吗？
- Go away, it's so late... - No, I was going to say that...
-走开，这么晚了你到底要干嘛？-不，我要说的是
You... Hey, what are you doing? Why are you going in?
你……你进来干什么？
Just a sec...
很快就好
You are going to write these down on computer.
把这些录入系统
Good morning to you too.
你也早上好
TO THE MINISTRY OF INTERIOR AFFAIRS
内政部
Come in!
进来吧！
What's this?
这是什么？
My resignation, sir.
长官，这是我的辞职报告
Really, I didn't get it...
我不明白
I can see that. I am asking why.
我知道是辞职信，我问你为什么
I have to do that...
我必须辞职
It's because of personal reasons. You'll put it in process.
因为个人原因，请您批准
I haven't had my coffee yet. I'm not awake yet.
我还没喝咖啡，还不清醒
Do you know what I'll do?
你知道我会做什么吗？
I'll take your resignation
我把你的辞职报告
and put it in my drawer.
放在我的抽屉里
And I'll give you five days off.
给你五天假期
Go home, get some rest, think this through
回家休息一下，想一想
and if you still want to resign after five days, I'll accept it.
如果五天后你仍然想辞职，我会接受的
I'll put your paper in process. Okay?
到时候我会批准，好吗？
- But, Chief... - Nevra!
-但是，长官 -Nevra！
Did you know that it was me who wanted you here at the bureau?
你知道是我想让你进警察局的吗
I chose you from 50 girls.
我从五十个女孩中选了你
It wasn't because your father was a cop.
不是因为你父亲是警察
Do you know why?
你知道为什么吗？
Because among those 50, it was only you determined to be
因为在那50个人中，虽然你的工作前景光明
a cop although you had a bright future in your job.
但只有你有决心做警察
I told myself that she was crazy and I needed someone crazy here.
我告诉自己她疯了，我恰好需要一个疯子在这里
Go home and think.
回家好好想一想
Yes?
你好？
Turn it down!
声音小一点！
She's driving me crazy.
她快把我逼疯了
She got crazy now she's making me crazy.
她疯了，现在要让我疯了
How can I help you?
有什么事吗？
I'm Agah, Agah Beyoglu, from the courthouse.
我是Agah，Agah Beyoglu，来自法院
- From the secretary. - Yes.
-您是秘书处的 -是的
It has been years...
已经好几年了……
I was thinking that you somehow look familiar.
我就觉得你看着很眼熟
I never forget a face that I saw.
我永远不会忘记我看到的每一张脸
- Welcome. - Thank you.
-欢迎 -谢谢
- Come, come in. - Thank you.
-进来 -谢谢
We were just having dinner.
我们正在吃晚餐
- Are you hungry? I can prepare for... - No, thank you.
-饿了吗？我可以准备…… -不，谢谢
I'm sorry, it's a bit messy.
对不起，有点乱
There was a girl cleaning the house but she ran away because of her.
有一个女孩负责打扫房子，但是她把人家吓跑了
Everyone runs away.
每个人都被吓跑了
Who would tolerate this?
谁能忍受这个？
Why don't you take your coat off?
你为什么不脱掉外套呢？
No thanks, I caught a cold.
不用了，我感冒了
- Get well soon. - Thanks.
-祝你快点好起来-谢谢
It's been 20 years, right?
已经20年了，对吧？
I guess so.
大概吧
Do you remember Agah?
你还记得Agah吗？
When I was working on archives.
当我做档案工作的时候
Celal from assize court recommended Agah, God bless him.
巡回法庭的Celal推荐Agah，上帝保佑他
- He died too... - Really, may he rest in peace.
-他也死了 -愿他安息
He went there every weekend.
他每个周末去那里
- Was it Kambura? - Yes, it was Kambura.
-是Kambura吗？-是的，是Kambura
Agah was working at the secretariat at Kambura Courthouse.
Agah在Kambura法院秘书处工作
You opened many files for me right?
您帮我查了很多文件，对吗？
We went there with you once.
我们曾经一起去过那里
We ate trout near the river, remember?
我们在河边吃鳟鱼，记得吗？
- She's been like this for four years. - What's wrong with her?
-她已经这样四年了-她怎么了？
It's bad, Agah, bad.
不好，Agah，很不好
She has Alzheimer's.
她患有老年痴呆症
Get well soon.
祝她快点好起来……
She won't get well.
她会好起来了
Look at her. She wasn't someone to be like this.
她不是这样的人
She's ruined.
她毁了
She ruined us too.
她也毁了我们
Our daughter is living in Madrid.
我们的女儿住在马德里
We went to visit her.
我们去拜访她
We watched a flamenco show there.
我们在那里看了弗拉门戈表演
All these things are from there.
所有这些东西都来自那里
How do they say...
怎么说呢……
Feza's only connection to life is these.
Feza与生活的唯一联系就是这些
I don't know why, her memory only kept these.
我不知道为什么，她的记忆只保留了这些
Otherwise she neither knows me nor our girl.
否则她既不认识我也不认识我们的女儿
Come on.
来吧
I take care of everything.
我要负责所有事情
I even clean her bottom.
我甚至要帮她擦屁股
Like I can take care after myself.
就像我可以照顾自己似的
So, Agah.
对了，Agah
- Are you retired? - Yes.
-你退休了吗？-是的
What was your wife's name?
你老婆叫什么名字？
Mebrure.
She passed away too.
她也去世了
May she rest in peace.
愿她安息
Thank you.
谢谢
So Agah, why did you come here?
Agah，你来这里有什么事情吗？
How did you find this place?
怎么找到这个地方的？
We thought weather is better on this side.
我们认为这边的天气更好
It's also far away from the crowds.
离人群也很远
May I use the bathroom if you don't mind?
如果您不介意，我可以用一下洗手间吗？
I've come a long way.
我走了很长一段路
Yes, sure.
没问题
I have the same problem.
我也是这样
My bladder and all are sagged...
我的膀胱都凹陷了……
Look, it's over there.
在那边
Come on, drink.
喝一口吧
Drink it woman!
把它喝掉！
- Drink it, come on! - Excuse me.
-喝吧，来吧！-对不起
Do you have farsighted glasses?
你有远视眼镜吗？
Yes, over there.
有，在那边
- It's on the shelf. - Thanks, I forgot mine.
-在架子上-谢谢，我忘了我的
I'm running out of patience, just take one sip!
我已经忍无可忍了，只喝一口！
Come on, at least take one sip.
来吧，至少喝一小口
So Agah, what are you doing around here?
Agah，你在这附近做什么？
I had work to do.
我有工作要做
If there is something we can do, just say it. Don't be shy.
如果有什么我们能帮忙的尽管说
Yes, of course. I will.
是的，当然了
I was nine years old.
我九岁的时候
The year was 1961.
那年是1961年
My mom had baked a cake for my birthday.
我妈妈为我的生日烤了一块蛋糕
That was the first time.
那是第一次
I made a wish blowing out candles.
我许愿吹蜡烛
My wish was this...
我的愿望是这样的
Back then
那时候
Yuri Gagarin was going to be the first man going to space.
尤里·加加林（Yuri Gagarin）将成为第一个进入太空的人
And I wished he would take me with him.
我希望他能带我走
I believed so much that my wish will come true
我非常相信我的愿望会成真，
I prepared a bag and started waiting.
我准备了一个包，开始等待
I thought they will come from The Soviet Embassy to get me.
我以为他们会从苏联大使馆来接我
But I was hearing that they were communists.
但是我听说他们是共产党员
People were saying "Careful, they are communists."
人们都说“小心，他们是共产党员”
I said then I'll be one too.
我说那我也做共产党员
During that time
那时候
college students were staying on the first floor.
大学生住在一楼
My mom was calling them communists too
我妈妈也叫他们共产党员
and I knew they had hidden books in our cellar.
我知道他们在我家的地窖里藏了书
I went there and stole one.
我去那里偷了一本
Poems of Nazim Hikmet.
Nazim Hikmet的诗歌集
I found the shortest one and memorized it.
我记住了其中最短的一个
I thought if the Russians came, I'd read this poem to them
我以为如果俄国人来了，我给他们读这首诗
and they'd think I was one of them and take me.
他们就会认为我是他们的一员然后带我走
Chief?
长官？
Anyways...
总之……
The date was April 12th.
那天是4月12日
The space shuttle was going to be launched.
航天飞机就要发射了
Vostok-1.
东方1号
But no one had come for me.
但没人来找我
I thought they forgot about me.
我以为他们把我忘记了
The shuttle was launched.
航天飞机发射了
Everyone was praying for the shuttle to go through the atmosphere.
每个人都在祈祷航天飞机穿过大气层
Only I was praying for it to return half way around to take me.
只有我在祈祷它能半途而来带我
And maybe the Americans
也许美国人
were praying for Vostok to not go into the space.
在祈祷Vostok不要进入太空。
Whatever.
随便了
All day long
那一整天
near the radio
在收音机旁边
I read that poem silently.
我默默地读那首诗
My head is a foamy cloud.
我的头是泡沫状的云
My inside and outside is a sea.
我的内外都是大海
I'm a walnut tree in Gulhane Park.
我是Gulhane公园的一棵核桃树
An old walnut tree. With long branches and pieces.
一棵老核桃树，长着树枝和碎片
Neither you are aware of this nor is the police.
你和警察都不知道这件事
I MET A GIRL YESTERDAY. HER NAME WAS NEVRA ELMAS.
我昨天遇到一个女孩。她的名字叫NEVRA ELMAS
Whenever I read this poem I feel like I go to space.
每当我读这首诗时，我都会觉得自己去了太空
I am 65 years old now.
我今年65岁了
I made a wish again, just like a child.
我像个孩子一样再次许愿
An impossible wish, of course.
当然是不可能实现的愿望
Do you know what I wished for?
你知道我想要什么吗？
To become a good person.
我想做个好人
Dad, I guess you are sleeping.
爸，我猜你在睡觉
It's over, I can't tolerate this man no more. We are moving back to Istanbul.
结束了，我不能再容忍这个人了，我们要搬回伊斯坦布尔
We are coming together with Deva.
我和Deva一起回去
I'll call you later.
我会再联系你
Good night.
晚安
FIRST FEMALE POLICE OFFICER OF HOMICIDE BUREAU
凶杀局的第一位女警官
她唯一的目标是成为一个好警察和一个好人
HER ONLY GOAL IS TO BE A GOOD POLICEMAN AND A GOOD PERSON